OSManemara (917) 977-0999 | emaraosman@gmail.com | www.osmanemara.com

github.com/emaraosman | linkedin.com/in/osmanemara

Full Stack Web Developer

Summary: Web developer with a knack for responsive design, featuring clean modular code with an acute eye for detail and modern design patterns. Utilizing technical expertise to produce RESTful websites with the latest technologies. Effective use of prior communication experience in conflict resolution and human resource techniques to better communicate client needs and navigate the lifecycle of website development.

Skills: JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, Express, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, SQL

Experience

General Assembly New York, NY

Engineer Fellow | Web Development Immersive

September 2017 – Present

- Built fluency in full-stack web development through completing an intensive three-month program focused on common best practices in object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and test-driven development.
- Tasked with learning RESTful web technologies including React.js, Node, Express, and Ruby on Rails
- Development occurring within set schedules, utilizing modern technologies for fully responsive custom websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and more.

Freelance Development

New York, NY

Web Designer/Brand Innovator

December 2016 – Present

- Tasked with building a client base and pursuing contracts with businesses in Manhattan.
- Working as a sole developer, tasks involved redesigning websites, improving online presence of businesses, and developing the brand of clientele.
- Development occurring within set schedules, utilizing modern technologies for fully responsive custom websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and more.
- Created professional photo and video solutions as per demand by client and branding needs.

Agios Pharmaceuticals Inc.

Cambridge, MA

Human Resources Administrator

September 2014 – May 2015

- Coordinated daily interviews for incoming candidates with executive level personnel at Agios, whilst creating and posting new official job descriptions for the Agios career website.
- Collaborated with IT department in updating and maintaining Microsoft SharePoint databases, employee profiles, and HR documentation.
- Participated in company-wide performance review processes and recruiting efforts, also aided in the hiring process and on-boarding orientation of over 60 new employees.
- Provided direct administrative support to Sr. HR manager and assisted in daily tasks involving extensive calendar management, scheduling of large and small scale meetings, and event planning.

Emara Academic Solutions, www.emarasolutions.com

New York, NY

Tutor 2013 - 2017

• Tutored students in high school level language skills, including English and Spanish and SAT/ACT exam prep

Education

Boston College, College of Arts & Sciences Bachelor of Arts in Political Science

Boston, MA

2010 - 2014

Resident Advisor